

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Chicago, IL USA

□ (224) 258-2804 | Scontact@rasheedsaad.com | www.rasheedsaad.com | srashee

# Summary\_

I'm currently a Software Engineer at Indeed writing customer facing full stack applications. I'm passionate about building, tinkering and making things better. I have experience developing on embedded systems, cloud technologies and machine learning platforms. I'm also attending University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign for Computer Science part time.

# Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

Indeed Research & Development

SOFTWARE ENGINEER II

May 2022 - Present

- Feature development, architecture and leadership on an Applicant Tracking System product.
- Worked with an offshore team to lead end to end software feature development.
- · Stakeholder communication to develop business requirements and bringing complex technical features to fruition.

**Accenture**Industry X

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER Apr 2021 - May 2022

- Leader on a team to contribute and build a healthcare e-commerce solution.
- Built automated tooling and HIPAA compliant full-stack applications using Salesforce solutions.
- · Scaled out a Smart City data ingestion pipeline while managing and developing multiple micro services in Kubernetes.

Motorola Solutions Secure Products Group

SOFTWARE ENGINEER II

- · Developed encryption software and security related features for the Motorola's next generation radio, APX NEXT.
- · Developed software across multiple teams across multiple countries and built solutions for cross team development.
- Developed and tested features for public safety related infrastructure.

### SOFTWARE ENGINEER I

- Worked on a security feature for the Motorola GRV Comparator.
- Developed test code for IoT TCP/UDP devices in C.
- Helped design and build automated infrastructure and tooling for embedded devices.

# Education

## **University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign**

Urbana-Champaign, Illinois

M.S IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

2019 - Present

Jan 2018 - Apr 2021

Relevant Courses: Distributed Systems (Cloud Computing), Parallel Programming, Theory and Practice of Data Cleaning, Text Information Systems, Foundations of Data Curation, Programming Languages & Compilers and Deep Learning for Healthcare.

### Northern Illinois University

Dekalb, Illinois

**B.S IN COMPUTER SCIENCE** 

2015 - 2017

- · Distinction: Cum Laude
- Relevant Courses: Data Structures, Algorithms, UNIX, Networking, Databases, iOS Mobile Programming, Assembler Mainframe, Java, Operating Systems, Computer Architecture and Systems

# Skills

- Languages: React, Java 11, C, C++, Python, Swift, SQL, Haskell, Javascript, YAML, and Scripting(Bash, PS1, Batch)
- **Tools:** Git, Docker, GDB, ARM debugger, npm, Clearcase, Jenkins, Github Actions, Docker, Kubernetes, Helm, Terraform, Artifactory, Conan, Jupyter, AWS, CMake, EKS, EC2, and SFRA
- Platforms: AWS, Azure, Windows, Linux, ARM, RHEL and Salesforce Commerce Cloud
- **Embedded:** GPIO, USB, Serial, RS232, and SPI Interfaces
- Security: Experience working with encryption algorithms, key management and OWASP Top 10

**Projects** 

Full Stack Application Under Construction

CLR MIND Jan. 2022 - Present

Building a full stack application that centralizes your day to day allowing you to have a clear mind.

Motorola YPG SCH Motorola Solutions

Social Branch Lead Jan. 2020 - Apr 2021

- · Led a team to setup events for Motorola social events.
- Event planning for virtual events during the pandemic.
- Event planning for social in-person events for 500 attendants.

Causal Data Mining CS410: Text Information Systems

ITERATIVE TOPIC MODELING WITH TIME SERIES FEEDBACK

October 2020

- Worked with a team to develop a system in Python to analyze historical data and build graphical associations with historical events.
- The project and code is an open-sourced research project available for viewing.

Google Extension Google Chrome Store

MINIMALIST Feb. 2019 - Present

- Developed and maintain a minimal note taking application for Google Chrome.
- Available for download in the Google Chrome Store.

# **ACM WCS Mentorship Program**

University of Illinois at UC

May. 2020

- · Mentored an Ungraduate Computer Science student.
- Met virtually on a regular cadence to help matriculation during the COVID 19 Pandemic.

Motorola Hackathon Schaumburg, Illinois

TECHNICAL ENABLEMENT LEAD

Jan. 2019 - Apr. 2019

- Led a team to setup required technical infrastructure for hackathon, hosting approximately 100 participants.
- · Team enabled participants to use GitLab, GitHub, Cloud Instances alongside proprietary Motorola hardware.

**iOS Application**Northern Illinois University

 Developed a social media iOS application in Swift 3 that allowed university students to sign up and communicate publicly through posts and images.

· Used Firebase for the back-end and data store to allow users to comment and like other user's posts.